Middleboro, Mass. First Church of Middleboro records, 1702-1925.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Membership records, 1741 1880; 1741-1880; 34 Folders
  - Marriage intentions: D-M, 1837 1852; 1837-1852 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Simeon W. Mitchell and Lydia M. Caswell, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 24, Item 57-58)
    - Timothy Mitchell and Lydia B. Tinkham, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 24, Item 59-60)
    - Charles S. Morse and Nancy W. Pratt, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 24, Item 61)
    - Henry S. Murry and Mary A. McAllister, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 24, Item 62)
  - Marriage intentions: N-R, 1837 1853; 1837-1853 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Thomas Nelson and Hope K. Harlow, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 1-2)
    - John W. Newhall and Mary Chamblin, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 3)
    - John O'Connell and Louisa Pratt, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 4)
    - Michael C. Onderdonk and Malancy Shaw, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 5-6)
    - Lucious J. Orent and Caroline F. Harrington, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 7-8)
    - George Osborn and Phebe W. Hall, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 9-10)
    - John Partridge and Sarah F. Cushing, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 11-12)
    - William S. Pierce and Hulah L. Washburn, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 13)
    - Pierce Penniman Jr. and Virtue M. Freeman, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 14-15)
    - David D. Perkins and Lucy Atwood, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 16-17)
    - Jason Perkins and Jerusha B. Holmes, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 18)
    - Nathan Perkins Jr. and Nancy Sias, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 19)
    - Lewis W. Perry and Charity S. Burt, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 20)
    - Dexter Phillips and Irene M. Warren, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 21-22)
    - Zenas Churchill Phinney and Cynthia Smith, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 23-24)
    - Edmund F. Pope and Charlotte A. Churchill, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 25)
    - Amos Pratt and Lucy M. Sproat, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 26-27)
    - Benjamin F. Pratt and Abigail B. Morse, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 28)
    - Benjamin F. Pratt and Hannah R. Baley, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 29-30)
    - Francis G. Pratt and Charlotte E. Eddy, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 31)
    - Orrin S. Pratt and Thalia E. McAllister, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 32)
    - William Pratt and Ann Elizabeth Eddy, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 33)
    - William W. Pratt and Sylvia Perkins, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 34)
    - William Loring Randall and Mercy A. Fuller, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 35-36)
    - Edward W. Raymond and Mary Atwood, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 37)
    - Henry A. Raymond and Susan M. Horton, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 38-39)
    - Isaac W. Record and Harriet D. Briggs, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 40)
    - Francis Reed and Mercy Pierce, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 41)
    - Levi Reed and Joanna W. Harlow, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 25, Item 42)
  - Marriage intentions: S, 1837 1852; 1837-1852 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Albert A. Savery and Elizabeth T. Shurtleff, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 1)
    - Benjamin M. Sears and Jane F. Bourne, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 2)
    - Edmund L. Sears and Lucetta J. Thomas, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 3-4)
    - Frederick A. Sekell and Mary. R. Sekell, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 5-6)
    - Alfred Shaw and Mary Morton, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 7)
    - Ebenezer D. Shaw and Nancy E. Bisbie, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 8)
    - Elijah Shaw and Lucy Shurtleff, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 9)
    - Francis S. Shaw and Abby S. Southworth, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 10-11)
    - Horatio Shaw and Lydia H. Staples, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 12-13)
    - John A. Shaw and Sophia A. Tinkham, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 14)
    - Luther Shaw and Abigail Cobb, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 15-16)
    - Lothrop Shurtleff and Nancy Sherman, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 17)
    - Lothrop Shurtleff and Elizabeth H. Whittemore, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 18)
    - Nathaniel Shurtleff 4th and Susannah Thomas, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 19)
    - Perey T Shurtleff and Eliza B. Leonard, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 20-21)
    - Reuben R. Simmons and Jane Morton, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 22)
    - George Sisson and Clarinda A. Macomber, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 23)
    - Ira Smith and Nancy D. Paddock, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 24-25)
    - Timothy Smith Bathsheba Caswell, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 26-27)
    - Jerome B. Snow and Naomi L, Reckard, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 28-29)
    - Samuel N. Snow and Angeline Dean, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 30-31)
    - Thomas Snow and Sally Dilaswell, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 32)
    - Venus Snow and Olive Willis, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 33)
    - Charles Soule and Mary Wilder, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 34-35)
    - Jacob Soule and Lydia Thompson, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 36-37)
    - John M. Soule and Betsey B. Harlow, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 38-39)
    - Jonathan Souler and Abigail R. Hayward, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 40)
    - Jacob Sparrow and Lois S. Macomber, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 41)
    - Josiah Sparrow and Clarisa H. Howard, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 42-43)
    - Ranville T. Sproat and Florantha Thompson, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 44)
    - Alfred C. Standish and Sarah A. White, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 45)
    - Miles Standish and Sarah C. Thomas, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 46)
    - Samuel M. Stevens and Priscilla S. Soule, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 47-48)
    - Croade Sturtevant and Lucinda Wood, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 49)
    - George Swan and Sarah Elizabeth Marshall, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 50)
    - Henry A. Swift and Emily A. Savery, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 26, Item 51)
  - Marriage intentions: T-W, 1837 1852; 1837-1852 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - James Taylor and Lois B. Tinkham, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 1-2)
    - Andrew Thomas and Louisa Vail, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 3)
    - Azel Thomas and Harriet Thompson, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 4)
    - Benjamin F. Thomas and Judith S. Thomas, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 5)
    - Harrison Thomas and Lucy F. Ricard, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 6)
    - Ichabod Thomas and Respah M. Thomas, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 7)
    - John L. Thomas and Almida E. Gammons, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 8-9)
    - Lorenzo Thomas and Martha Atwood, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 10)
    - Lothrop Thomas and Louisa F. Thomas, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 11)
    - Nathanial Thomas and Emeline Thomas, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 12)
    - Nelson Thomas and Harriet A. Maxham, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 13-14)
    - Perez Thomas and Sarah Cobb, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 15)
    - Robert M. Thomas and Susan H. Barker, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 17)
    - Seneca Thomas and Zilpah B. Shurtleff, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 18)
    - Stephen Thomas and Almira Thomas, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 19)
    - Winslow Thomas and Mary Thomas, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 20-21)
    - Benjamin F. Thompson and Sarah A. Wood, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 22)
    - Francis Thompson and Dorlisea N. Vinica, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 23)
    - Ichabod Thompson and Lucy T. Carver, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 24-25)
    - Isaac Thompson and Ann T. Thompson, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 26-27)
    - israel W. Thompson and Lydia R. Walker, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 28)
    - Martson Thompson and Harriet G. M. Bump, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 29)
    - Reuel Thompson and Sarah T. Wood, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 30)
    - Thomas F. Thurston and Ruth P. Raymond, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 31)
    - William Tillson and Clara S. Thompson, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 32-33)
    - Alvah Tinkham and Elizabeth Vaugham, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 34)
    - Ira Tinkham and Hannah McAllister, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 35)
    - Oliver G. Tinkham and Jane Freeman, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 36-37)
    - Reland Tinkham and Lavinia Weston, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 38)
    - Silas Tinkham and Angelina B. Hathaway, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 39)
    - Benjamin F. Tripp and Pauline Bryant, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 40-41)
    - Sidney Tucker and Sarah Ann Nelson, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 42)
    - David C. Vaughan and Patience Atwood, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 43)
    - Harrison W. Vaughan, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 44)
    - Jabez Vaughan and Joanna Willis, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 45-46)
    - William H. Vaughan and Salome Willis, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 47)
    - Benjamin F. Warren and Lydia J. Bump, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 48)
    - James W. Warren and Hannah C. Tribou, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 49)
    - Lewis F. Warren and Zilpha M. Clark, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 50)
    - Azel Washburn 2nd and Anne Strawbridge, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 51-52)
    - Ellis Weston and Abigail B. Robbins, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 53)
    - Henry Weston and Martha W. Eddy, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 54)
    - Thomas Weston and Maria L. Tillson, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 55-56)
    - Perry A. Wilbur and Betsey B. Wilder, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 57)
    - David Wilder and Mary E. Thompson, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 58-59)
    - George W. Williams and Fanny M. Shaw, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 60)
    - John Augustus Williams and Sarah Harlow, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 61-62)
    - John S. Williams and Hepzabeth B. Harlow, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 63)
    - Andrew C. Wood and Lucy Ann Miller, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 64)
    - Benjamin F. Wood and Louisa Wood, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 65)
    - Eliah Wood Jr. and Mary C. Freeman, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 66)
    - Martin Wood and Lydia Vinica, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 67-68)
    - Samuel N. Wood and Eveline Willis, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 69-70)
    - Thomas J. Wood and Mary Tinkham, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 27, Item 71)
  - Membership requests, 1827 1873; 1827-1873 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Dismissions, 1834 1877; 1834-1877 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sabina Willis, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 1)
    - Rev. Israel Putnam, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 2)
    - Julia Ann Putnam, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 2)
    - Adeline Osgood, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 2)
    - Temperance Wood, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 3)
    - Ann Perkins (Nelson), 1838 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 4)
    - Betsey Pratt, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 5)
    - G. Eddy, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 6)
    - Charles Eddy, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 7)
    - Henry Dunham, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 8)
    - Alfred Wood, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 9)
    - Hary Harlow Thompson, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 10)
    - Halford Earle, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 11)
    - Elizabeth Earle, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 12)
    - Phebe Wood (Hamilton), 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 13-14)
    - Consider Robbins, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 15)
    - Bethiah Harlow, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 16)
    - Abigail Pickens, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 17)
    - Mary Briggs, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 18)
    - Cornelius Burgess, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 19)
    - Melissa Burgess, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 20)
    - John Perkins, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 21)
    - Henry Hitchcock, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 22)
    - Olivia Hitchcock, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 23)
    - Joanna Brand, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 24)
    - Almira Goddard, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 25)
    - George Leach, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 26)
    - Ezekiel Goss, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 27)
    - Melinda Eddy, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 28)
    - Adeline Cobb, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 29)
    - Saba Adams Comstock, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 30)
    - Susan Caswell, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 31)
    - Eliva Eddy, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 32)
    - Lydia Shaw (Sampson), 1853 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 33)
    - Elizabeth Pratt, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 34)
    - Mary Fuller, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 35)
    - Clara Pease, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 29, Item 36)
  - Dismission to Central Church, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Disciplinary matters, 1741 1847; 1741-1847 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Elmes versus Pratt controversy and testimony, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Religious society membership certificates, 1830 1835; circa 1830-1835 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - John Fuller boarding house advertisement, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    This advertisement was removed from the Marriage intentions: D-M folder.
- Ministerial records, 1832 1891; 1832-1891; 8 Folders
  This series contains records pertaining specifically to the ministers of the First Congregational Church in Middleboro. Included in this series are correspondence, receipts, letters related to dismissions, and disciplinary records. Also included are the invitations the church received to the ordinations and dismissions of other area ministers.
  - Reverend William Eaton, 1832 1834; 1832-1834 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Reverend Rufus M. Sawyer, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Reverend Ephraim N. Hidden, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Reverend Nathan T. Dyer, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Reverend Howard A. Hanaford, 1885 1886; 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Reverend Josiah W. Kingsbury, 1888 1891; 1888-1891 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Invitations to installations and ordinations, 1835 1864; 1835-1864 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Invitations to pastoral dismissions, 1835 1863; 1835-1863 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Manuscript sermons, 1737 1779; 1737-1779; 6 Folders
  This series contains the manuscript sermons of the Reverends Peter Thatcher and Sylvanus Conant. Both ministers were revivalist preachers and Conant was an avowed supporter of American independence.
  - Peter Thatcher sermon, 1737 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    This manuscript sermon was digitized as part of the New England's Hidden Histories project. Digital reproductions are available to view online.
    This single sermon on Acts 2:37, originally delivered by Rev. Peter Thatcher of Middleboro in 1737, was copied and preached subsequently by his great-grandson at the First Church of Middleboro, in February of 1847.
  - Sylvanus Conant sermons, 1744 1747; 1744-1747 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    These manuscript sermons were digitized as part of the New England's Hidden Histories project. Digital reproductions are available to view online.
    This folder contains a significant number of sermons by Rev. Silvanus Conant, delivered between 1744 and 1747. They were preached both at his own church in Middleboro and also in neighboring parishes.
    Index of Sermons
    Colossians 3:1
    "If ye then be risen with Christ, seek those things which are above, where Christ sitteth on the right hand of God…"
    Psalms 119:2
    "Blessed are they that keep his testimonies, and that seek him with the whole heart…"
    Malachi 3:1
    "Behold, I will send my messenger, and he shall prepare the way before me: and the Lord, whom ye seek, shall suddenly come to his temple, even the messenger of the covenant, whom ye delight in: behold, he shall come, saith the Lord of hosts…"
    Leviticus 26:23-24
    "And if ye will not be reformed by me by these things, but will walk contrary unto me; Then will I also walk contrary unto you, and will punish you yet seven times for your sins…"
    Ephesians 2:1
    "And you hath he quickened, who were dead in trespasses and sins…"
    Habakkuk 2:4
    "…but the just shall live by his faith…"
    Matthew 27:51
    "And, behold, the veil of the temple was rent in twain from the top to the bottom; and the earth did quake, and the rocks rent…"
    Canticles 8:7
    "Many waters cannot quench love, neither can the floods drown it: if a man would give all the substance of his house for love, it would utterly be condemned…"
    Romans 1:17
    "For therein is the righteousness of God revealed from faith to faith: as it is written, The just shall live by faith…"
    Luke 17:32
    "Remember Lot's wife…"
    Amos 3:6
    "Shall a trumpet be blown in the city, and the people not be afraid? shall there be evil in a city, and the Lord hath not done it?"
    Deuteronomy 32:5
    "They have corrupted themselves, their spot is not the spot of his children: they are a perverse and crooked generation…"
    Acts 16:14
    "whose heart the Lord opened, that she attended unto the things which were spoken of Paul…"
    Luke 10:20
    "Notwithstanding in this rejoice not, that the spirits are subject unto you; but rather rejoice, because your names are written in heaven…"
    Matthew 22:4
    "All things are ready: come unto the marriage…"
    "Shall there be evil in a city, and the Lord hath not done it?"
    Canticles 1:12
    "While the king sitteth at his table, my spikenard sendeth forth the smell thereof…"
    Jeremiah 2:13
    "For my people have committed two evils; they have forsaken me the fountain of living waters, and hewed them out cisterns, broken cisterns, that can hold no water…"
    Ruth 1:16
    "And Ruth said, Intreat me not to leave thee, or to return from following after thee: for whither thou goest, I will go; and where thou lodgest, I will lodge: thy people shall be my people, and thy God my God…"
    James 3:17
    "But the wisdom that is from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, and easy to be intreated, full of mercy and good fruits, without partiality, and without hypocrisy…"
    James 1:19
    "Wherefore, my beloved brethren, let every man be swift to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath..."
    Revelations 5:9
    "…and hast redeemed us to God by thy blood out of every kindred, and tongue, and people, and nation…"
  - Sylvanus Conant sermons, 1748 1749; 1748-1749 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    This folder continues with Rev. Silvanus Conant's sermons through the years 1748-1749. Most of them appear to have been preached first at Middleboro, and often at other venues subsequently.
    1 Peter 5:8
    "Be sober, be vigilant; because your adversary the devil, as a roaring lion, walketh about, seeking whom he may devour…"
    Galatians 5:18
    "But if ye be led of the Spirit, ye are not under the law…"
    Matthew 22:42
    "Saying, What think ye of Christ? whose son is he? They say unto him, The son of David…"
    1 Corinthians 2:12
    "…that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God…"
    2 Corinthians 6:17
    "Wherefore come out from among them, and be ye separate, saith the Lord, and touch not the unclean thing; and I will receive you..."
    2 Corinthians 3:18
    "But we all, with open face beholding as in a glass the glory of the Lord, are changed into the same image from glory to glory, even as by the Spirit of the Lord…"
    Psalms 110:7
    "He shall drink of the brook in the way: therefore shall he lift up the head…"
    Isaiah 26:20
    "Come, my people, enter thou into thy chambers, and shut thy doors about thee: hide thyself as it were for a little moment, until the indignation be overpast…"
    Mark 10:52
    "And Jesus said unto him, Go thy way; thy faith hath made thee whole. And immediately he received his sight, and followed Jesus in the way…"
    Psalms 103:17
    "But the mercy of the Lord is from everlasting to everlasting upon them that fear him, and his righteousness unto children's children…"
  - Sylvanus Conant sermons, 1770 1776; 1770-1776 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    This folder represents the latest dated sermons preached by Rev. Conant, during the course of the 1770s, until his death from smallpox in 1777.
    Isaiah 40:15-17
    "Behold, the nations are as a drop of a bucket, and are counted as the small dust of the balance: behold, he taketh up the isles as a very little thing…All nations before him are as nothing; and they are counted to him less than nothing, and vanity…"
    Matthew 18:20
    "For where two or three are gathered together in my name, there am I in the midst of them…"
    Ephesians 6:4
    "And, ye fathers, provoke not your children to wrath: but bring them up in the nurture and admonition of the Lord…"
    1 Peter 1:5
    "Who are kept by the power of God through faith unto salvation ready to be revealed in the last time…"
    Isaiah 45:22
    "Look unto me, and be ye saved, all the ends of the earth: for I am God, and there is none else…"
    Genesis 24:63
    "And Isaac went out to meditate in the field at the eventide: and he lifted up his eyes, and saw, and, behold, the camels were coming…"
    Jeremiah 5:9
    "Shall I not visit for these things? saith the Lord: and shall not my soul be avenged on such a nation as this?"
    1 Timothy 1:15
    "This is a faithful saying, and worthy of all acceptation, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners; of whom I am chief…"
    2 Timothy 2:3
    "Thou therefore endure hardness, as a good soldier of Jesus Christ…"
    John 10:11
    "I am the good shepherd…"
    Ephesians 1:11
    "In whom also we have obtained an inheritance, being predestinated according to the purpose of him who worketh all things after the counsel of his own will…"
    1 Corinthians 13
    "If I speak in the tongues of men and of angels, but have not love, I am a noisy gong or a clanging cymbal..."
  - Sylvanus Conant sermon, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    In this single sermon preached in May of 1776, Rev. Conant urges humility among his congregants and discusses how errant brethren should be dealt with according to Matthew 18:15-18.
  - Sylvanus Conant sermons, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    This folder contains Rev. Conan's undated sermons.
    Romans 5:11
    "And not only so, but we also joy in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, by whom we have now received the atonement…"
    Romans 5:1
    "Therefore being justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ…"
    Philip 1:6
    "Being confident of this very thing, that he which hath begun a good work in you will perform it until the day of Jesus Christ …"
    Hebrews 2:3
    "How shall we escape, if we neglect so great salvation; which at the first began to be spoken by the Lord, and was confirmed unto us by them that heard him…"
- Publications, 1759 1925; 1759-1925; 11 Items
  This series contains printed materials published by, and for, the First Congregational Church in Middleboro. The series includes published sermons, printed versions of the covenant and confession of faith, and historical accounts of the church.
  - The Art of War, the Gift of God, 1759; Conant, Sylvanus, 1720-1777 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The Confession of Faith and Church Covenant, 1771 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - On the Unity of Christ's Church, 1807; Barker, Joseph, 1751-1815 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - A Discourse at the Ordination of the Rev. Emerson Paine, 1816; Williams, Thomas, 1779-1876 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The Articles of Faith and Covenant, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - An Account of the Great Revival in Middleborough, Mass. A. D. 1741, 1742, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Public worship circular, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Two Discourses on the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Author's Ordination, March 15th, 1815, 1865; Putnam, Israel W. (Israel Warburton), 1786-1868 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - A Sermon Preached at the Funeral of Rev. Israel Warburton Putnam, D. D., 1868; Dexter, Henry Martyn, 1821-1890 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Ordination and Installation of Nathan T. Dyer, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Will Honor an Historic Church, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 47)